{"test_questions": [[{"question": "CUP : LIP :: BIRD : ?", "opta": "BUSH", "optb": "GRASS", "optc": "FOREST", "optd": "BEAK", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Cup is used to drink something with the help of lips. Similarly birds collects grass with the help of beak to make her nest."}, {"question": "Flow : River :: Stagnant : ?", "opta": "Rain", "optb": "Stream", "optc": "Pool", "optd": "Canal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As Water of a River flows similarly water of Pool is Stagnant."}, {"question": "Paw : Cat :: Hoof : ?", "opta": "Lamb", "optb": "Elephant", "optc": "Lion", "optd": "Horse", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As cat has Paw similarly Horse has Hoof."}, {"question": "Ornithologist : Bird :: Archealogist : ?", "opta": "Islands", "optb": "Mediators", "optc": "Archealogy", "optd": "Aquatic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As Ornithologist is a specialist of Birds similarly Archealogist is a specialist of Archealogy."}, {"question": "Peacock : India :: Bear : ?", "opta": "Australia", "optb": "America", "optc": "Russia", "optd": "England", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As Peacock is the national bird of India, similarly Bear is the national animal of Russia."}, {"question": "REASON : SFBTPO :: THINK : ?", "opta": "SGHMJ", "optb": "UIJOL", "optc": "UHNKI", "optd": "UJKPM", "ans": "B", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Carbon : Diamond :: Corundum : ?", "opta": "Garnet", "optb": "Ruby", "optc": "Pukhraj", "optd": "Pearl", "ans": "B", "explanation": "As Diamond is made of Carbon similarly Ruby is made of Corundum."}, {"question": "NATION : ANTINO :: HUNGRY : ?", "opta": "HNUGRY", "optb": "UHNGYR", "optc": "YRNGUH", "optd": "UNHGYR", "ans": "B", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Architect : Building :: Sculptor : ?", "opta": "Museum", "optb": "Stone", "optc": "Chisel", "optd": "Statue", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As 'Architect' makes 'Building' similarly 'Sculptor' makes 'Statue'."}, {"question": "Eye : Myopia :: Teeth : ?", "opta": "Pyorrhoea", "optb": "Cataract", "optc": "Trachoma", "optd": "Eczema", "ans": "A", "explanation": "As Myopia is disease of eye similarly pyorrhoea is a disease of teeth."}, {"question": "Conference : Chairman :: Newspaper : ?", "opta": "Reporter", "optb": "Distributor", "optc": "Printer", "optd": "Editor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As Chairman is the highest authority in a conference similarly Editor is in Newspaper."}, {"question": "Safe : Secure :: Protect : ?", "opta": "Lock", "optb": "Sure", "optc": "Guard", "optd": "Conserve", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As safe ans secure have same meaning in the same way protect and guard have same meaning."}, {"question": "Master : OCUVGT :: LABOUR : ?", "opta": "NCDQWT", "optb": "NDERWT", "optc": "NBERWT", "optd": "NEDRWT", "ans": "A", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Microphone : Loud :: Microscope : ?", "opta": "Elongate", "optb": "Investigate", "optc": "Magnify", "optd": "Examine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As Microphone makes sound louder similarly Microscope makes the object magnified."}, {"question": "Melt : Liquid :: Freeze : ?", "opta": "Ice", "optb": "Condense", "optc": "Solid", "optd": "Force", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As on melting, liquid is formed similarly on freezing solid is formed."}, {"question": "College : Student :: Hospital : ?", "opta": "Nurse", "optb": "Doctor", "optc": "Treatment", "optd": "Patient", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As Students read in College similarly Patients are treated in Hospital."}, {"question": "Tree : Forest :: Grass : ?", "opta": "Lawn", "optb": "Garden", "optc": "Park", "optd": "Field", "ans": "A", "explanation": "As Tree is found in Forest similarly Grass is found in Lawn."}, {"question": "South : North-West :: West : ?", "opta": "North", "optb": "South-West", "optc": "North-East", "optd": "East", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As North-West is 135o clockwise from South in the same were North-East is 135o clockwise from the West."}, {"question": "Cloth : Mill :: Newspaper : ?", "opta": "Editor", "optb": "Reader", "optc": "Paper", "optd": "Press", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As Cloth is made in a Mill, similarly Newspaper is printed in press."}, {"question": "Country : President :: State : ?", "opta": "Governor", "optb": "M.P", "optc": "Legislator", "optd": "Minister", "ans": "A", "explanation": "As President is the nominal head of a country, similarly Governer is the nominal head of a State."}, {"question": "Race : Fatigue :: Fast : ?", "opta": "Food", "optb": "Laziness", "optc": "Hunger", "optd": "Race", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As the result of Race is Fatigue similarly the result of Fast is Hunger."}, {"question": "Peace : Chaos :: Creation : ?", "opta": "Build", "optb": "Construction", "optc": "Destruction", "optd": "Manufacture", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As opposite meaning of peace is chaos similarly opposite meaning of creation is destruction."}, {"question": "Tiger : Forest :: Otter : ?", "opta": "Cage", "optb": "Sky", "optc": "Nest", "optd": "Water", "ans": "D", "explanation": "As Tiger is found in Forest similarly  Otter is found in the water."}, {"question": "Poles : Magnet :: ? : Battery", "opta": "Cells", "optb": "Power", "optc": "Terminals", "optd": "Energy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As magnet has poles similarly battery has terminals."}, {"question": "Cassock : Priest :: ? : Graduate", "opta": "Cap", "optb": "Tie", "optc": "Coat", "optd": "Gown", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A Priest wears cassock while Graduate wears gown."}, {"question": "Ice : Coldness :: Earth : ?", "opta": "Weight", "optb": "Jungle", "optc": "Gravitatism", "optd": "Sea", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As effect of Ice is coldness similarly the effect of Earth is gravitation."}, {"question": "Parts : Strap :: Wolf : ?", "opta": "Fox", "optb": "Animal", "optc": "Wood", "optd": "Flow", "ans": "D", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Physician : Treatment :: Judge : ?", "opta": "Punishment", "optb": "Judgement", "optc": "Lawyer", "optd": "Court", "ans": "B", "explanation": "As Physician does the treatment similarly Judge delivers the judgement."}]]}